williamsf1.com 2019-04-04

# Privacy Policy | Williams

PRIVACY POLICY

Williams Grand Prix Engineering Limited (company number 1297497) **(“Williams” / “we” / “our” / “us”)** takes your privacy very seriously and is committing to protecting your personal data. 

If you wish to contact us regarding this privacy policy, please see the contact details ** _here_**. Williams is the data controller and our registered office is Grove, Wantage, Oxfordshire, OX12 0DQ.

This privacy policy (together with the terms and conditions, which you can find _**[here](http://www.williamsf1.com/policies/terms-and-conditions)**_  ) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us through your use of our website ([http://www.williamsf1.com](http://www.williamsf1.com/)) and any sub-domains (the “Website”), will be processed by us.  

This privacy policy does not apply to websites that you may be able to access via links on the Website and/or activities offered by third parties. We are not responsible for the collection or use of your personal data from these third party websites.  Please ensure you review any relevant policies.

**TOPICS COVERED** :

  * **DATA WE COLLECT FROM YOU OR ABOUT YOU AND OUR SOURCES OF THAT DATA**
  * **PURPOSE AND LEGAL BASIS FOR PROCESSING YOUR PERSONAL DATA**
  * **MARKETING **
  * **DISCLOSURE OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA **
  * **WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**
  * **SECURITY **
  * **RETAINING PERSONAL DATA **
  * **YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS **
  * **COOKIES**
  * **CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY **
  * **HOW TO CONTACT US** ****

**Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.**

**DATA WE COLLECT FROM YOU OR ABOUT YOU AND OUR SOURCES OF THAT DATA**

We will collect, use, store and transfer the following data about you: 

  * **Data you give us.**   You may give us data about you: 
    * by filing in a form on the Website.  For instance, when you complete the “SAY HELLO” form on the Website;  
    * when you register your details to gain behind the scenes access at Williams and agree to receive: 
      * newsletters with exclusive news and team updates; 
      * competition notifications; 
      * notifications about how to visit Williams; 
      * team merchandise offers; and 
      * updates on exclusive fan events; 
    * if you ask us to provide you with other marketing communications; 
    * if you ask us to provide you with personalised online content such as targeted advertising; 
    * when entering a competition or prize draw;
    * when you place an order on the Website and during our fulfilment of such order; 
    * if you contact us or correspond with us (for example, by phone, email or otherwise) for any other reason, for example, to find out more about Williams Heritage or to enquire about and/or book an event with us; or 
    * when you provide us with comments, opinions and/or feedback or when you complete a survey, for example, about the Website or any of our products.
    * when you register for our Paddock Club web application (at vip.williamsf1.com);
  * **Data we collect about you.** We will collect the following personal data about you: 
    * technical information, including the type of device (and its unique device identifier) you use to access the Website, the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your device to the Internet, your login information, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug in types and versions, operating systems, mobile network information and platform; and 
    * information about your visit to the Website including full Uniform Resource Locators (URL), clickstream to, through and from the Website (including date and time), pages you viewed, page response time, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page. 
  * **Data we collect from or which is provided by third parties.** We may be given personal data about you by third parties such as the operator of the shop.williamsf1.com™ at the Website, ticket sales websites and social media platforms, or anyone making a booking on your behalf for you to attend Williams’ site. ****

**PURPOSE AND LEGAL BASIS FOR PROCESSING YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We will use the **personal data** held about you for the purposes stated below:

**Purpose of Processing**

| 

**Type of personal data**

| 

**Legal basis for processing**  
  
---|---|---  
  
To process and deliver any order you place directly with Williams, including managing payments, fees and charges and collect and recover money owed to us.

| 

Your name, email address, password, billing address, delivery address, credit or debit card details and phone number. 

| 

Performance of a contract.   
  
To manage our relationship with you, including 

-       dealing with any enquiries, correspondence, concerns or complaints you have raised with us;

-       notifying you about changes to our terms and conditions and privacy policy; or 

-       asking you to leave a review or take a survey. 

| 

Your name, email address, address, job title, company name, opinion and information about any concerns or issues you have raised. 

| 

Performance of a contract and our legitimate interest – to enable us to keep our records updated and to better understand our fans, guests and customers.   
  
To enable you to partake in a prize draw, competition or complete a survey. 

| 

Your name, email address, job title, company name, phone number and address details. 

| 

Performance of a contract and legitimate interest – to enable us to understand our fans and customers better.   
  
To allow you to attend the Williams site when visiting the Williams Conference Centre or any other area.

| 

Your name, email address, phone number and address details. 

| 

Legitimate interest – to enable us to provide you with access.   
  
To register you for behind the scenes access. 

| 

Your name, email address, password, date of birth and country of residence or your Gmail, Facebook, Twitter or Microsoft details.  

| 

Legitimate interest – to enable you to manage your profile.   
  
To register you for the Williams VIP web application. 

| 

Your name, email address, job title, company name and password.

| 

Legitimate interest – to enable you to register for the Williams VIP web application.   
  
As part of our efforts to keep the Website safe and secure. 

| 

Your personal contact details and the technical information mentioned above. 

| 

Legitimate interest – to improve and ensure the safety of the Website.   
  
To compile reports (which do not personally identify you) about the use of the Website. 

| 

The technical information mentioned above. 

| 

Legitimate interest – to improve the Website.   
  
To ensure that content on the Website is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your device. 

| 

The technical information mentioned above.  ****

| 

Legitimate interest – to improve the Website.   
  
To deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you.

| 

The technical information mentioned above. 

| 

Legitimate interest – to understand our fans better, keep the Website updated and relevant and to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy.   
  
To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences.

| 

The technical information mentioned above. 

| 

Legitimate interest – to understand our fans better, keep the Website updated and relevant and to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy.   
  
To better understand our audience. 

| 

The technical information mentioned above, email address, address, date of birth, job titles and which organisation you are from. 

| 

Legitimate interest – to allow us to prepare statistical information to be used internally to better understand our fans, but also to be shared with our advertisers in non-personally identifying form to enable them to understand who their adverts are presented to and who they wish to target for advertising purposes.   
  
To provide you with marketing communications, for example, newsletters, updates and notifications. 

| 

Your name, postal address, phone number or email address. 

| 

Consent.   
  
To provide you with marketing communications with information about our sponsors and partners and news and updates about their services, activities and products.  

| 

Your name, postal address, phone number or email address

| 

Consent.   
  
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about products, services or events that may be of interest to you.

| 

Your name, date of birth, email address, postal address, phone number or the technical information mentioned above. 

| 

Consent.   
  
To provide you with marketing communications in respect of shop.williamsf1.com, which is operated by Fanatics. 

| 

Your name, email address or social media handle. 

| 

Consent.   
  
To provide personalised online content to you (via the Website, social media platforms or our online partners). 

| 

The technical information mentioned above, your name and email address. 

| 

Consent.   
  
Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you. 

Where we have a legal basis to use your personal data without consent (as we have described above), this policy fulfils our duty to process personal data fairly and lawfully and in a manner that you would expect given the nature of our relationship with you, by giving you appropriate notice and explanation of the way in which your personal data will be used. 

Where consent is required for our use of your personal data, by ticking the appropriate consent box or otherwise communicating your consent, you consent to our use of that personal data for the purposes covered by the specific consent that you have given.  For example, we will only process your personal data for marketing purposes if we have your consent to do so. 

**MARKETING**

As mentioned above, we would like to send and present you with information about Williams which may be of interest to you. 

We will provide your details to our partners, including Fanatics (International) Limited, only if you have consented to this (and only to the persons that are covered by your consent), but we will **not** provide your personal data to other businesses so they can use your personal data for marketing purposes.

We will only send and present you with marketing communications if you would like us to. You will have the opportunity to clearly set out whether you wish to receive marketing communications from us by ticking the relevant boxes.

**DISCLOSURE OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We may share your personal data with selected third parties in accordance with this policy, including: 

  * with Fanatics (International) Limited, who are the operator of shop.williamsf1.com™ at the Website and who would be contracting with you should you wish to purchase any products via the shop.williamsf1.com, but only if you have consented to this.  A link to their privacy policy can be found **_[**_here_**](https://shop.williamsf1.com/stores/williams/en/help?helpSection=privacy)_** ;
  * with our partners, but only if you have consented to this and then only to those of our partners for whom you have given consent.  A list to our current partners can be found ** _[here](http://www.williamsf1.com/racing/about/our-partners)_** ** _._**
  * with Google, Facebook, Twitter and Microsoft (if you use your account with them to sign up / in with us), if applicable; 
  * service providers (for example, IT services or CRM services), business partners, suppliers and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with you, but also when sending out marketing communications; 
  * professional advisers acting as processors or joint controllers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services; 
  * any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006; 
  * analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of the Website; 
  * government or other law enforcement agencies, in connection with the investigation of unlawful activities or for other legal reasons (this may include your location information); or 
  * a third party where all or substantially all of our assets are acquired by such third party, in which case personal data held by us, including your personal data, will be one of the transferred assets (however, we will let you know before this happens).

**WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

The personal data that we collect from you is not transferred to or stored at destinations outside the European Economic Area ( **EEA** ).

If you would like to find out more about this or obtain a copy of the relevant standard contractual clauses, please contact us at The Legal Department, Williams Grand Prix Engineering Limited, Grove, Wantage, Oxfordshire, OX12 0DQ or by email at [legal.department@williamsf1.com](mailto:legal.department@williamsf1.com).

**SECURITY**

All the information you provide us with is stored on secure servers.  We will use technical and organisation measures to safeguard your personal data. 

Where you have chosen (or we have given you) access details and/or a password which enable you to access your Williams team profile, you are responsible for keeping these access details and password confidential.  We ask you not to share your access details and password with anyone. 

We maintain (and ensure that anyone we share your personal data with maintains) **** appropriate technical and organisational measures to ensure that an appropriate level of security in respect of all personal data we process. Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to the **** Website and you acknowledge that any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features which are appropriate to the type of personal data you have provided to try to prevent unauthorised access or inadvertent disclosure.

**RETAINING PERSONAL DATA**

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes for which we collected it, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements. To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data so that it can no longer be associated with you, in which case we may use such information without further notice to you.

Even if you request that we erase your data, we may still need to keep it (please see below) or may keep it in a form that doesn’t identify you.  Unless you have an account on our website (to gain behind the scenes access) or you have agreed that we may use your personal data for marketing purposes (for example, to provide you with team updates and other marketing communications), we will only keep your personal data for six years after you have made a purchase from us or via the Website.  Please note that where you make a purchase through a webpage which is operated by a third party (eg via shop.williamsf1.com or if you buy tickets for the Williams Conference Centre which are sold by The Ticket Factory), you should refer to their privacy policies for further information as to how your data is handled and how long it is kept.

**YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS**

You have the following rights with regard to your personal data: 

  * **Access.**   You have the right to access data we hold about you.  This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it. 
    * **Rectification or erasure**. You have the right to request that we rectify or delete any personal data that we hold about you (unless we have the legal right to retain it). This right does not extend to non-personal data. Please note that your rights to request erasure may be limited by applicable law. 
    * **Restriction**.  You also have the right to restrict us from processing your personal data if the data is inaccurate, the processing is unlawful or we no longer need your personal data for the purposes for which we hold it.  
    * **Data portability.** You have the right **** to obtain personal data we hold about you, in a structured, electronic format, and to transmit such data to another data controller if the legal basis for processing such personal data is consent. 
    * **Object /change of preferences**. You have a right to request that we stop processing your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party). You have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes.  For example, if you have given your consent to receive team updates or other marketing communications, but have changed your mind, you have the ability to opt out from receiving such communications going forward by contacting us using the details provided below or by clicking the relevant link in any communications you receive. 
    * **Complaints.** If for any reason you are not happy with the way that we have handled your personal data, please contact us. If you are still not happy, you have the right to make a complaint to the Information Commissioner’s Office. 

Please note that if you ask us to stop processing your personal data in certain ways or erase your personal data, and this type of processing of data is needed to facilitate your use of the Website or the provision of products or services to you, you may not be able to use the Website or receive products or services from us as you did before.  This does not include your right to object to direct marketing, which can be exercised at any time without restrictions. Please allow at least ten working days for your request to be actioned. 

Please note that the rights mentioned above do not extend to **non-personal data**. 

If you would like to exercise any of the rights mentioned above, please contact us at The Legal Department, Williams Grand Prix Engineering Limited, Grove, Wantage, Oxfordshire, OX12 0DQ or by email at legal.department@williamsf1.com.

**COOKIES**

We use cookies, which are small files of letters and numbers that we store on your browser or the hard drive of your computer if you agree.  Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer’s or mobile device’s hard drive. 

We use the following cookies: 

  * **Strictly necessary cookies**. These are cookies that are required for the operation of the Website. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas of the Website, use a shopping cart or make use of e-billing services.
  * **Analytical/performance cookies**. They allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around the Website when they are using it. This helps us to improve the way the Website works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily.
  * **Functionality cookies**. These are used to recognise you when you return to the Website. This enables us to personalise our content for you, greet you by name and remember your preferences (for example, your choice of language or region).
  * **Targeting cookies**. These cookies record your visit to the Website, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We will use this information to make the Website and the advertising displayed on it more relevant to your interests. We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose.

We use Google Analytics which is an analytical / performance cookie. The Website uses Google Analytics to help analyse how users use the Website, collecting standard internet log information and visitor behaviour information in an anonymised form from which no user is identifiable. We have also implemented Google Analytics features based on Display Advertising ([Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2799357?hl=en)).

This information is transmitted to Google and processed to compile statistical reports on activity on the Website and so be able to develop the Website and its content around our users’ interests. These reports allow us to optimise our user experience. Google provide a browser add-on for users who wish to prevent their data from being used by Google Analytics.

Click [here](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en) and [here](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en) for an overview of privacy at Google, and click [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) if you wish to opt out from the operation of Google Analytics.  In addition, you can use the [Google Analytics Opt-Out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) to disable tracking by Google Analytics.

You can find more information about the individual cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them in the table below: 

**Cookie**

| 

**Expiration**

| 

**Purpose**

| 

**Origin**  
  
---|---|---|---  
  
_gid

| 

24 hours

| 

This is a Google cookie that is used to distinguish users.

| 

.williamsf1.com  
  
_gat

| 

1 minute

| 

This is a Google cookie that is used to throttle request rate.

| 

.williamsf1.com  
  
_ga

| 

2 years

| 

This is a Google cookie that is used to distinguish users.

| 

.williamsf1.com  
  
SC_ANALYTICS_GLOBAL_COOKIE

| 

1 year

| 

This is a Sitecore Engagement Analytics Cookie which identifies repeat visits from a single user. This expires one year after the last page requested by a user. It doesn’t identify individuals using the website.

| 

.williamsf1.com  
  
williamsf1#lang

| 

End of Session

| 

Sitecore cookie to track a user’s language selection.

| 

.williamsf1.com  
  
williamsf1#accept-consent

| 

365 days

| 

Tracks whether a user has consented to the use of cookies.

| 

.williamsf1.com  
  
williamsf1#marketing-opted-out

| 

End of Session

| 

Tracks whether a user has cleared a message about opting in to marketing communications.

| 

.williamsf1.com  
  
ASP.NET_SessionId

| 

End of Session

| 

Used to identify the users session on our web server. 

| 

.williamsf1.com  
  
.AspNet.ApplicationCookie

| 

End of Session or when user explicity logs out.

| 

Authentication cookie for users who have logged into our identity site.

| 

.williamsf1.com  
  
__RequestVerificationToken

| 

End of Session

| 

Anti-forgery token used to help prevent CSRF attacks.

| 

.williamsf1.com  
  
fr

| 

3 months

| 

Facebook Analytics cookie. Contains a unique browser and user id.

| 

.facebook.com  
  
vimeo, __qca, __gads, continuous_play_v3, player, _abexps, vuid, is_logged_in, _ga, has_logged_in, _ceg.s, _ceg.u, __ssid, has_uploaded, _mibhv, sst_aid, sst_uid

| 

Dates are set in the cookies themselves and may vary in length, depending on the purpose of the cookie.

| 

To display and deliver videos on our site, we make use of Vimeo, a video sharing website. The embedded Vimeo player, uses these cookies to check if certain features or preferences have been selected by the user. To find about more about how each cookie is used by see [Vimeo’s cookie list.](https://vimeo.com/cookie_list) More information can be found on [Vimeo’s privacy policy.](https://vimeo.com/privacy)

| 

.vimeo.com  
  
ARRAffinity

| 

End of Session

| 

Cookie which ensures a user stays on a specific instance of a website or web app in Azure.

| 

.williamsf1.com  
  
__cfduid

| 

1 year

| This is a tracking cookie to allow notifications to be sent to the user. | 

.onesignal.com  
  
By clicking “agree” in the cookie consent box when you first access the Website and by continuing to access and use the Website you accept the use of the cookies.

You can block cookies by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or part of the Website. 

For more detailed information about cookies and how they can be managed and deleted, please visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). 

**CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

Any changes we make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page, where appropriate, or notified to you by e-mail.  Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy. 

Continued use of the Website will signify that you agree to such changes. 

**HOW TO CONTACT US**

Questions, comments and requests regarding our privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to The Legal Department, Williams Grand Prix Engineering Limited, Grove, Wantage, Oxfordshire, OX12 0DQ or by email at legal.department@williamsf1.com. 

Please also contact us if you would like to know more about our data processing activities, to update or amend any of your personal data which you have provided to us or if you believe our records relating to your personal data are incorrect.

Our privacy policy was last updated on 13 March 2019.

Version: PP-2019-03
